# ANSHUL RAHEJA

Email: anshul.raheja97gmail.com

DOB: 16-Oct-1997

Delhi

# **EDUCATION**

B.tech (CSE)

Dr. Akhilesh Das Gupta Institute of Technology and Management

2016-2020 | CGPA: 8.3

#### 12th

St. George's 2015-2016 | **88.6%** 

#### 10th

St. George's 2013-2014 | **89.3**%

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: React | JavaScript |
CSS5 | HTML | Nodejs | MongoDB |
Java | SQL | Git | Github | OOPS |
Data Structure and Algorithm

**Soft Skills:** Problem Solving | Analytical Thinking | Focused | Persistent | Adaptive

## **EXTRA-CURRICULAR**

Volunteer

Josh Talks | June 2019

Part of the Event Management Team for 2 days. My responsibilities were to help the production team in various activities and oversee the smooth running of the shoot.

#### Marketing

Entrepreneurship Cell | 2018 - 19

Active Marketing Member in organizing the Annual Internship Fair in my college and bringing various companies onboard as recruiters.

## Operations

Awaaz- Cultural Society | 2016-17 Performed various roles and activities to successfully organize Annual College Fest 2017

## **SUMMARY**

Front End Developer with 1+ years of corporate experience in building products using JavaScript, Java & SQL.

Highly focused to grow my career in front-end web app development to build visual and interactive elements for the best user experience.

Working on Reactjs for all my projects. With my current skill set and more experience to come in the future, I aspire to integrate my problem-solving and designing skills to excel as a Full-Stack Web Developer.

## MY WORK

Portfolio Website: https://anshulraheja.netlify.app

Github: <u>anshulraheja</u> LinkedIn: <u>anshul-raheja</u> Leetcode: <u>anshulraheja</u>

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer**

Newgen Software | Feb 2020 - June 2021

- Implementation of Newgen Products.
- Understanding of object-oriented design, data structure, and algorithms.
- Proficiency in the digitization of the Insurance process.
- Execute full software development lifecycle (SDLC) and knowledge of associated issues.
- Deployment of the complete solution.
- Requirement Gathering, Client Interaction & Discover Solution.

Software Used: BPM, ECM, CCM

Tech Stack Used - Java, Javascript, SQL

## **INTERNSHIPS**

#### **Business Development Executive**

Extramarks Education Pvt Ltd | Jan 2020 - Feb 2020

- Develop strategies to boost a company's sales and overall growth.
- Present the company's product to the customer through phone calls and F2F interaction.
- · Conducting research to analyze client's needs.
- Summarize the weekly progress and achieve the target.

## **Team Leader**

AIESEC | Feb 2018 - Oct 2018

- Member of Incoming Global Volunteer Department for the 1st guarter.
- Facilitated international student exchanges who worked as volunteers in schools & NGOs across Delhi along with handling two teams who helped in the facilitation and smooth functioning of all processes.
- Experience management and tracking for 10+ volunteers coming to Delhi and looked over the legalities of the exchange including the contracts, exchange product policies, and other relevant matters.

## **PROJECTS**

## **Automatic Image Caption Generator**

Major Project | 2020

A model that uses deep learning/Al technology to form meaningful sentences by interpreting images.

Tech Stack Used - Python

## **Motorcycle Crash Detection and Alert System**

Minor Project | 2019

A device that detects accidents through sensors and acts as an informant to riders close aid in case of emergency.

Tech Stack Used - Java, Android, Arduino Uno programming